So, you just learned how to demean a factor so that the values add up to zero.
你刚刚学习了如何对因子去均值 使值相加等于 0
But why do we do this,
但是为何要这么做呢？
the short answer is that, later on,
简单的答案就是
we're going to test the factor as if each value
我们将检验因子
associated with each stock also determined,
就好像与每支股票相关的每个值
the stock weight in a theoretical portfolio.
同时确定了理论投资组合的股票权重
We want to make this theoretical portfolio dollar neutral, that is,
我们希望这个理论投资组合保持美元中性
the dollar amount of all long positions equals the dollar amount of all short positions.
也就是所有做多头寸的金额等于所有做空头寸的金额
We want to do this to test the predictive power of
我们希望检验因子的预测效果
the factor while excluding the influence of the overall market.
并且排除总体市场的影响
So, why is a dollar neutral portfolio less influenced by overall market movement?
为何总体市场变化对美元中性投资组合的影响更小？
Well, market movement refers to
市场变化是指
the general direction of most stocks in a country or region.
某个国家/地区大部分股票的一般走向
If a portfolio was long only,
如果投资组合仅做多
it would likely move in the same direction as the market.
它可能与市场的走向一样
If a portfolio was short only,
如果投资组合仅做空
it would likely move in the opposite direction of the market.
它可能与市场的走向相反
A long short portfolio means we can take long and short positions.
做多和做空投资组合是指同时做多和做空
A dollar neutral portfolio is a special case of a long-short portfolio.
美元中性投资组合是一种特殊的做多和做空投资组合
Is the case where the value of the longs equals the values of the shorts.
即做多的金额等于做空的金额
If a portfolio were halfway along and have short,
如果投资组合一半做多 一半做空
then the market movement would have
那么市场变化
a minimal effect on the movement of this dollar neutral portfolio.
对这个美元中性投资组合的影响最小
So, a dollar neutral portfolio is set up to approximately be market neutral.
所以美元中性投资组合大致保持市场中性
Note that, an assumption we're making is that on average
注意 我们假设
the Beta of each stock to the market is one.
每支股票相对于市场的 Beta 平均值为 1
Remember that, Beta in
在资本资产定价模型中
the capital asset pricing model refers to how much a stock moves when the market moves.
Beta 是指当市场变化时 股票变化多少
In general, the average Beta of stocks may not be exactly one,
通常 股票的 Beta 平均值不一定完全等于 1
but when a portfolio contains thousands of stocks it's a reasonable assumption.
但是当投资组合包含数千支股票时 这种假设比较合理
So, a dollar neutral portfolio may move a bit with
所以美元中性投资组合可能因为市场变化而变化一点点
the market but it would ideally be close to market neutral.
但理想情况下接近市场中性
Let's now switch from talking about portfolio positions in dollar
下面我们从以金额表示的投资组合头寸
amounts to talking about portfolio positions in terms of weights.
变成以权重表示的投资组合头寸
Let's review the meaning of portfolio weights and introduce the concept of the notional.
我们回顾下投资组合权重的含义并介绍下名义这个概念
The notional or trade book value is the gross dollar amount associated with a portfolio.
名义价值或交易账面价值是指与投资组合相关的总金额
The amount of money we'd allocate towards a stock equals its
分配给股票的金额等于
portfolio weight times the portfolio's gross notional value.
投资组合权重乘以投资组合的总名义价值
If a portfolio notional is 100 million and the stock is given a weight of 0.01,
如果投资组合的名义价值为 1 亿美元 股票权重为 0.01
we multiply the weight of 0.01 times 100 million which is 1 million.
那么用权重 0.01 乘以 1 亿 等于 100 万美元
This would be the amount of money we'd allocate toward the stock.
这就是我们要分配给该股票的金额
For a long or short portfolio,
对于做多-做空投资组合
we can also use the weight times the notional
我们还可以用权重乘以名义价值
to see the dollar value placed on that stocks position,
看看分配给股票头寸的金额
whether it's a long position or short position.
无论是做多头寸还是做空头寸
For example, assuming a notional of 100 million,
例如 假设名义价值为 1 亿美元
let's say we have a stock with a weight of 0.01
假设股票的权重为 0.01
this translates to a position of $1 million.
所以头寸为 100 万美元
Likewise, another stock with a weight of negative
同理 另一个权重为 -0.01 的股票
0.01 then has a position of negative $1 million.
头寸为 -100 万美元
Notice in this example,
注意 在此示例中
assuming that there are only two stocks in the portfolio,
假设投资组合只有两支股票
these positions add up to zero.
这些头寸的和等于 0
When all the positions add up to zero,
当所有头寸相加后等于 0 时
the portfolio is dollar neutral.
投资组合就是美元中性
Remember, the goal of having a dollar neutral portfolio is to make
美元中性投资组合的目的是
the portfolio market neutral or at least close to market neutral.
让投资组合保持市场中性或至少接近市场中性